hello everybody my name is green and
welcome back to another hermitcraft
episode look at how much i have made and
look what are the progress i've made
underwater now there's a bit of a
problem that i'm encountering now is
that
this is going to be extraordinarily
tall and thin which is not what i was
after
when i started making this build i did
want it to appear much
much wider than it is right now so there
might be a little bit of a rearrange and
redesign that happens at some point but
today we're gonna well we seem to be
starting every episode off with some
kind of transaction
and today is no different i'm poor i am
dirt poor i've got five diamonds to my
name that is meansly it can't do
anything with that and for some reason i
got potatoes everywhere anyway
what i'm doing today just to start us
off is to try and get a bit more
diamonds to my name without having to
grind too much
so i've got cobblestone galore and i'm
selling to jevin who desperately needs
cobblestone so i've managed to secure a
deal of 208
stacks of cobble that's a lot of
cobblestone
for 32 diamonds so we're gonna quickly
deliver that to him
take his time i somehow feel like this
isn't worth it but i don't really know
the value of things so i'm a very easy
target hopefully this is a pretty good
deal i'm not entirely sure
hello hello oh the cobblestone delivery
guys here
yes hey
come down to my workshop good sir i did
promise i'd deliver it in person
yes i
must admit evan like i don't i've well
this is like my first uh
proper
sale where i'm selling and i've never
done it before so i don't know whether
i'm getting fleeced here or not so
i uh i gotta be honest with you i i feel
like you're getting a pretty good deal
so i have seven empty ones that i can
give you to replace those
excellent and
here is your payment good sir there we
go that's literally that's most of the
cobble i have and i have a feeling i'm
seriously going to regret this at some
point i like i feel like at one point i
mean hermitcraft goes on for nearly a
year a season
yeah i'm probably gonna regret giving
away so much stone and cobble i just i
feel it i feel it yeah well thank you
for the cobblestone sir and i hope that
you enjoy all of those diamonds i will
i'm gonna go and buy some pickles
not making enough money so i need to go
and buy my own all right bye
speaking of diamonds let's head over to
the pickle shop now it's actually been a
few days and i've had a few messages
from some of the other hermits telling
me that they're not too happy
with the design of my shop and then i
heard yep there it is iskal has put
something on the top now i haven't
actually seen this until now but i
definitely knew that this was coming
because lots of people told me and i i
couldn't escape it but oh my goodness
what is that it's a massive pickle
coming out the top of my pickle jar what
does this say
you're a pickle harry oh no are they
making fun of me i don't look like harry
potter well i to be fair lots of people
say that i look like harry potter in
real life so maybe that's where it is
come from this is a pretty fun build do
you think i should keep it there to be
honest with you it doesn't make any
difference i think i'm gonna keep it
it's a giant pickle i i can't complain
in any way whatsoever
it's a pretty it's a very well made
pickle you're a pickle harry
i love it well thank you iskall for
building uh
well a bit of you put a bit of height on
my pickle jar it's definitely more
noticeable and there's a couple of other
things that we need to do while we're
here
one we actually need to make a way out
because several people
have perished
in this pickle and here's a couple of
shots of that happening
of course the next question is how does
one exit
there is no way out of here at least not
that i can find
for real he did that
he made a shop with no exit
no way
that's actually hilarious
hopefully can rock it out of here
so much for that the other thing that we
need to do is oh someone's gonna water
logged the chests but i forgot to water
log some of these chests and oh my
goodness
people were getting very upset at me so
i've gone ahead and done that they're
all waterlogged now
there we go no harm no foul
oh my goodness we sold some pickles
any more
we actually made some money guys eight
diamonds i made a profit of eight measly
diamonds it's not very much at all but
it definitely wasn't worth the day and a
half i'm put into making this
but it's pretty good nonetheless anyway
we definitely need to go
and
in here because otherwise people are
never gonna come shopping here
so you could say that this pickle was a
total total success and i i think that's
that's a pretty fair assessment of the
whole thing we actually got some money
and we got a couple of laughs as well i
think that some people aren't
particularly happy with what i've done
but i happen to think that it was pretty
funny in general
and for those of you that are kind of
new to my channel i do like to play the
odd practical joke i've officially added
an exit it is a it's a little bit
obvious i guess but
the shop is supposed to have one at the
end of the day go straight up and out
the back you can't get back wait you
could swim down there but
it's probably very unnoticeable anyway
so that kind of settles the whole
pickle shops and shenanigans for now we
have well it looks okay we've got jar of
pickles iskall has built a
harry potter
pickle on top and then we've got our
shop which now has a functioning exit
but most importantly
we've made eight diamonds which is
absolutely nothing for the amount of
time i put in there i would have been
better off getting some diamonds by hand
oh well i'll just add that to the small
pile of diamonds that i've got and
that's a job well done and also in the
meantime i have still been working on
the base i've made even more progress
and it takes such a long time to make
anything on this thing now this is the
underwater segment and i'm not entirely
happy with it yet remember this is all
a work in progress this will change the
most but this is actually going the
direction that i want it to
what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna sort of
create another ring with a little bit of
a gap between these two
and i'm essentially gonna make this
shape go
up
overhang a little bit
and then double back
and create what hopefully
will seem almost like a muffin shape so
it'll go round and over but that's going
to take a huge
huge amount of time to get right and i'm
a little bit scared to start it in case
it ends up being
well like the underwater segment which
is a little bit thin that the problem is
i think that this looks a little bit too
thin that's my biggest issue with it it
just looks like it's not standing on
enough so i've actually completed all
the way around
this it's consistent all the way around
i've checked multiple times that there
are no errors
and it does look pretty good the only
thing is there isn't actually an
entrance if you want to go in you're
gonna have to go in through
this little hole in the middle
there we go so there's actually a fair
amount of space down here and i'm
thinking i'm gonna leave this water for
now until i can decide what i want to do
with it
my conduits down here i had to move it
from squidward and it's all going pretty
well actually i think everything so far
is going okay not perfect but okay
the next thing that i want to do
is i want to keep that pickle shop
completely stocked up we're going to
make a quick little pickle farm that
will just solve any pickle problems
because i want to actually light up a
lot of the ocean around me as well and
i'm going to need a fair amount of
pickles to do that so
we're going to quickly make a farm and
yes i am following a tutorial i didn't
make this in any way it's just a means
to an end so let's get into it
[Music]
so this is the pickle native 3000 this
is a design that i found on youtube and
it's hard to credit the original creator
because it's hard to tell who that is
there's a lot of clones or very similar
designs to this but i recommend checking
out ill mango because he's got some
pretty cool tutorials anyway this is the
pickle nature and i'm pretty sure that
it works after an hour of building it so
if we go up here hit this lever
it pulses just at the right time
should be able to see pickles just
appearing
occasionally and then the pistons push
them down breaking the pickles and then
they fall through here
working with water has been a total pain
but at the end of the day this has been
fairly all right and it's as well as
producing pickles i just gotta wait a
little while
and they're slowly appearing while the
pickle farm is churning away we're just
going to start lighting up the sea floor
because pickles are so less
that they're just much more subtle than
these giant sea lanterns
so i'm gonna just start replacing these
with pickles eventually and it should
look really really nice
also
nobody's mentioned not even once that
there's a shipwreck right next to my
base i barely noticed this for some
reason i don't know why it's here
i don't know how it must have been here
for forever i don't know if i've seen
this before i'm starting to wonder why i
chose the shipwreck over there when this
one is
i think it's a little bit more complete
than my one i don't know what's inside
though
well maybe zuma or somebody's been in
here
oh no there's a little bit there's a
little bit of swag in here i've got
potatoes there's a full
there's a full set of leather stuff but
i'm gonna take those carrots as i'm
pretty sure
i've not got any yet so that's pretty
useful yeah that's not not a bad little
bit of swag in there shipwreck but it is
missing it is definitely missing pickles
that's the only thing i'll say about it
the shipwreck is pretty cool but it
needs more pickles swimming along
singing a song planting pickles all day
long pickles
pickles on the seafloor pickles
pickles on the seafloor i just sang that
song and i can't even remember how it
goes now
some of these songs that i do are just
there just once and i shouldn't ever
sing because i don't have the voice for
it i should be banned from singing it
should be illegal that's like my version
of the
ho
ho bits of the work we go
it's it's the pig it's the sea pickle
song let's see if this has made any
difference whatsoever that has actually
made a world of difference
you can really see
exactly where the pickles are but
they're not so
in your face like the sea lanterns are
they it just looks like part of the
greenery which is really really nice the
guns
pickles on the seafloor pickles
pickles on the seafloor planting pickles
all day long i also read a bunch of
comments and i haven't been here since
it was made this is the pineapple under
the sea made by scar and people have
told me that he's left me
a gift from aquascar so that's that is
good times with scar and he's left me a
trident an unbreaking three mending
trident how awesome is that
i haven't i haven't actually used the
trident once we need to go and find
something to throw it at now where are
the monsters at
anything i can see
are fish
maybe we can hit one of the fish
oh
straight in the noggin that's made a
pretty big difference i'm probably gonna
have to spread the light even further
i'm gonna have to light up a lot of the
ocean for this to look really good and
i'm gonna have to get rid of those sea
lanterns but overall
i think lighting up the sea floor
has been a really good thing
really good thing and someone said that
sea pickles are useless look at that
looks gorgeous
if i do say so myself i imagine that
this is done
we are out of bone meal so this is
everything not too shabby i mean it's
only been running a few minutes so
not too bad that's probably enough to
restock the shop with and that's all we
really needed so there we have it the
pickle shop is restocked and that leaves
just one more thing that i really want
to do this episode
and that is doc's phantom run now i was
told to go to the nho go to the nether
follow the signs and i should be able to
find it i don't know what to expect at
all
okay
so this is it the nho nature reserve
whatever that is up nha oh phantom run
here we go i feel like i actually need
directions like i need a full map of the
server to do this
i speedway take a boat to the phantom
run okay
[Music]
oh my goodness this is so fast
whoa
that's so cool oh wait i'm not finished
oh my goodness this is so fast how fast
am i traveling exactly
really fast oh oh this is going to be
i'm so excited the build-up for this has
been amazing we're on a mooshroom island
oh my goodness
i've never seen a coral reef yet
i haven't seen one i haven't explored
far enough i've just taken i've sort of
used cubs shop to buy what i need
aren't they beautiful i mean they needed
to be because they are beautiful in real
life but i must say they've done a
really good job on this update that is a
really nice sight to see okay i'm
getting distracted i'm getting way too
distracted so that's the coral reef so
that's another thing that i've now seen
in this update and now we need to go and
do the phantom run wherever that is i
imagine it's this thing over here this
spooky looking thing over here whatever
this is
it's like been
i'm going to do a phantom run i don't
need phantoms right now thank you
where are you
hello
i hear but i don't see wait a minute
they're probably coming from the phantom
run
okay
please read the instructions carefully
before entering
why did i hit the button oh this sounds
terrifying this is like the most
terrifying thing ever oh let's hit the
locker room first shall we
let's get let's let's get rid of all of
our stuff let's read the instructions
while this screaming goes on welcome to
the phantom death run only the best and
strongest minecraft players for example
the nho and hermits can master this
challenge if you hesitate you are dead
make sure you read
make sure to carefully read the
instructions one press the button
once don't spam you fool pass through
the airlock and then walk straight
through the doors as they open look at
the phantom in front of you and wait you
cannot hit any phantoms if you do it's a
fine of five diamonds per hit should a
phantom die you'll get sued okay so
don't kill the phantoms put all of your
belongings in a locker chest sleep and
set your spawn go in naked you cannot
take any items with you in the dungeon
you're allowed to bring food to
regenerate health the best the best
players manage to make it without food
note down the amount of tries and deaths
and your episode name and number show
only the strong survive
okay
well doc you've done a good job of
scaring me
let's just do it
the airlock is opening
walk in
it's gonna close
okay
i can do this
run for your life
oh
hello mr phantom
i don't know what are you doing
oh
oh i see oh
maybe if i just stay here
i will
i'll survive
oh the screaming it's horrible
okay
okay you can do it green
where are they
haven't seen any yet
no no
two hits and you're out two hits and
you're out two hits in your
where where do i go where do i where do
i go where do you go where do you go
where do you go
oh go go down
oh i'm safe underwater oh my goodness
oh my goodness let's regenerate no i
think i'm underwater
you're definitely not safe underwater
oh
should we try this again one more try
let's try this again and we know to keep
moving all right you just gotta the key
here is to keep moving
okay
round two phantoms
okay let's go it's not even dilly dally
let's just go straight for it
let's get around the corner here around
the corner around the corner around the
corner
and the corner around the corner you're
not allowed to hit them don't look at
him don't look at him don't look at him
just try and dive try and dive
dive try and dive go go go go go go go
go go go go go go go go
they're not scary they're not how am i
i'm what i'm stuck
okay okay okay okay okay where am i
going the hardest part is to know where
you're going
there's a way out it's way out way up
way up way up way up
okay okay okay okay
wait did i
did i do it
i think i made it
i thought it was gonna be way longer
than that
i think i did it was that my second or
third try i think that's my second try
that definitely needs to be longer but
that was so good
right so green
episode 8
and i had one death
look at that
some people had didn't even die
not too shabby i'm happy with that i
made it on my second run
that is terrifying we need to get out of
here we need to get out of here right
now this is that's too stressful
too stressful that was a lot of fun a
lot of stress but a lot of fun
i'll be honest i don't actually remember
where i didn't know where i was going i
didn't know what i was doing
oh my goodness
well well done doc that was a lot of fun
and i definitely won't be doing it again
and that pretty much does it for this
episode of hermitcraft if you look at
that that is pretty much all the well
that's a lot of progress that has been
made on the base not gonna lie that is a
huge amount of resources and time that
have gone into that and you can imagine
just how tall this is going to get and
once i've added in some towers it's
going to look really futuristic in other
news
mumbo and i had a pretty long discussion
yesterday about some plans and ideas
what we're going to do in the long run
is connect up our two bases with a super
speedy highway he has been working on
these biomes and i actually helped him
out yesterday by making him an example
tree and it looks like he's done a
pretty good job
of replicating it so he's just had them
sort of droop over that looks really
cool well done mumbo so i kind of made
like a little example and he's made some
slightly smaller versions and i saw told
him to do some rocks and he's done a
really good job well done mumbo this
this looks brilliant
he's added in a lot of uh like proper
terraforming i gave him a few tips on
how to
terrain and terraform and i've got to
say he's he's done pretty well done
pretty well indeed so the plan for
architects at the moment is for both of
us to try and finish our bases in some
way get some machines going
and then eventually we're going to link
these up in some way with a super speedy
highway and we're gonna pull some
shenanigans on the server and create
some awesome things so eventually
this will all link up and become one
giant
architect hq alright so goodbye from me
and goodbye from paul that's right paul
you're saying goodbye thank you very
much for watching everyone good bye